<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://kskpd.pl/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kskpd.pl/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intangible - Pass It On</title>
      <link>http://kskpd.pl/en/projects/demoscene-as-a-community-album/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kskpd.pl/en/projects/demoscene-as-a-community-album/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the support of the National Heritage Institute under the &amp;ldquo;Intangible – Pass It On&amp;rdquo; program, and in cooperation with the distinguished sociologist Dr. Patryk Wasiak, we have released an album titled &amp;ldquo;Polish Demoscene as a Community. Informal Practices of Polish Demoscene Contacts&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Our goal was to gather, preserve, and disseminate knowledge about the communication practices and the creation of their own identity by the Polish demoscene. The same demoscene that we managed to register on the National List of Intangible Cultural Heritage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;ve released an alubm!</title>
      <link>http://kskpd.pl/en/blog/weve-released-an-alubm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kskpd.pl/en/blog/weve-released-an-alubm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the support of the National Heritage Institute within the &amp;ldquo;Intangible – Pass It On&amp;rdquo; program, and in collaboration with the distinguished sociologist Dr. Patryk Wasiak, we released an album titled &amp;ldquo;Polish Demoscene as a Community. Informal Practices of Polish Demoscene Contacts&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNESCO Anniversary Gala</title>
      <link>http://kskpd.pl/en/blog/unesco-anniversary-gala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kskpd.pl/en/blog/unesco-anniversary-gala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our representation, consisting of Andrzej &amp;ldquo;angelo&amp;rdquo; Lichnerowicz and Łukasz &amp;ldquo;zenial&amp;rdquo; Szałankiewicz, was invited to &lt;a href=&#34;https://nid.pl/2023/10/07/swieto-niematerialnego-dziedzictwa-kulturowego-2/&#34;&gt;The Celebration of the Intangible Cultural Heritage Festival in Zakopane&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polish Entry to UNESCO</title>
      <link>http://kskpd.pl/en/projects/polish-entry-to-unesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kskpd.pl/en/projects/polish-entry-to-unesco/</guid>
      <description>The demoscene is an international community creating digital audio-visual works. The artists&amp;rsquo; tools are electronic devices. Programs, music, and graphics are created on a variety of computer equipment, often pushing beyond its technical specifications — all in the name of art.&#xA;The Social Committee “Chronicle of the Polish Demoscene” closely cooperated with demoscene teams, cultural organizations, and individuals conducting research on digital culture and art.&#xA;It all began somewhere in 2019, from a tweet announcing the creation of the international initiative The Art of Coding, aimed at recognizing demoscene creativity as craftsmanship and art, whose development is part of the contemporary history of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We got this!</title>
      <link>http://kskpd.pl/en/blog/we-got-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kskpd.pl/en/blog/we-got-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The creativity of our demoscene now belongs to the digital heritage of Polish culture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And now, buckle up because it&amp;rsquo;s going to be classy. Thanks to the involvement of the Polish demoscene community, the Chronicle of Polish Demoscene Committee created and submitted an application for entry into the National List of Intangible Cultural Heritage. Today, a signed document has reached us. The application was accepted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demoscena X UNESCO</title>
      <link>http://kskpd.pl/en/blog/demoscena-x-unesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kskpd.pl/en/blog/demoscena-x-unesco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend, a lecture by Andrzej &amp;ldquo;unjello&amp;rdquo; Lichnerowicz titled &amp;ldquo;Demoscene: UNESCO Digital Heritage&amp;rdquo; took place at a multi-platform demoparty, organized by the Polish demoscene &lt;a href=&#34;https://xenium.rocks/&#34;&gt;Xenium&lt;/a&gt; 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology Matters</title>
      <link>http://kskpd.pl/en/page/technika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kskpd.pl/en/page/technika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Demoscene creativity is inseparably linked to computer technology. Digital art began to emerge in Poland the moment the first microcomputers appeared. Since then, it has been developing, often exceeding the technical specifications of computer systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Demoscene is Digital Culture</title>
      <link>http://kskpd.pl/en/page/sztuka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kskpd.pl/en/page/sztuka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The demoscene is an international community that creates digital audio-visual works. The tools of the artists are electronic devices. Programs, music, and graphics are created on a variety of computer equipment and often surpass its technical specifications — all in the name of art. The Social Committee “Chronicle of the Polish Demoscene” closely cooperates with demoscene teams, cultural organizations, and individuals conducting scientific research on digital culture and art.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Team</title>
      <link>http://kskpd.pl/en/page/about-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kskpd.pl/en/page/about-us/</guid>
      <description>We come from the Polish demoscene community, which knows us by our artistic pseudonyms. Here are our real names:&#xA;Andrzej Lichnerowicz Łukasz Szałankiewicz Kaja Mikoszewska Bartosz Rakowski Filip Kuźmiński Przemysław Ostrowski Daniel Koźmiński Luiza Bojczuk </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
